[music]
>> Hello everyone and welcome to this
session. My name is Volodymyr Synchuk
and I'm a software developer with
application team.
Today I'm going to show you
a new purchase order matching capability
that we introduce with this release.
If you work with purchase orders and
purchase invoices, you might have seen
situation where in when vendor invoice
arrives before goods are received or
when one invoice covers multiple
receipts
or even multiple order lines.
Current functionality assumes that
posted receipts exist
which is not always the case for real
world scenarios.
And even if receipt exist
current get receipt line experience will
only allow you to match one invoice line
to one receipt line, which is also a
limitation.
You might also seen situation where you
have a simple purchase orders that you
just want to receive when you invoice
arrive.
With this new functionality,
you will be able to match invoice line
to
one or multiple non-received order lines
as well as to many
partial receipt lines and you will also
be able to
auto post order receipt when posting
matching invoice.
So now let's see how it all works and
let's start with the scenario where we
match one invoice line to
multiple
non-posted order lines and then we post
receipt and then we post matched
invoice.
So here I have two
orders
for the same vendor, same item.
And I want to
invoice both of them with one incoming
invoice.
So I create a new invoice document.
And from here
I have
I have two ways
of matching it to the order lines.
I can use
a new
get order lines action that will show me
all available order lines and here I can
choose
in this case
uh
it will create one invoice line per one
order line, which is not what we want
for for this example, so I'm just go and
create
the line manually.
Now line is there and I go to new
matched order line user interface.
What I can do here
I can do several stuff, but let's start
with a
get in order lines themselves. So those
are open order lines. I'll select both
and I
match them here.
I got indicator that we got some order
matched for this invoice. So what I'm
going to do now, I'm going to
go back to orders and post received.
To make it a little bit more interesting
I'm going to post a full receipt of the
first one
and I'm going to
post
two partial receipts for the second one.
Now let's go back to the invoice and see
what we got here.
So now the order the invoice is only
matched to order lines. If I try to post
it now, there will be an error that it
has to be
matched at least one receipt line.
So what I can do here, I can get receipt
lines
for this specific order or I can just
reuse get order lines
and then it will automatically add all
existing
posted receipts.
So now we have
>> [snorts]
>> the entire picture here. We have
invoice line on top and then we have
order line and receipt lines in a tree
structure.
You can also see that uh
quantity to invoice is editable, meaning
that you can invoice receipt partially.
But for the purpose of this demo, let's
let's just invoice them completely.
So I'm going to go and post the invoice.
Yes, I want to open posted invoice.
And now I have a history of all the
matching, so I can keep it. Yeah.
And analyze.
And then if I just jump to
for example receipt, I can see that
quantity invoice is same as quantity
received
and same
for the order.
You can see that it is
fully received and fully invoiced. And
by the way, I can also see all my
invoices from from the lookup.
That was first scenario, which will
probably
be the most common use. And as for the
second scenario, let's let's explore how
we can auto post receipts together with
invoices.
For the second scenario, let's see how
our
auto receive functionality works.
So I have two orders
which are simple ones and I don't want
to
do anything complex with the receipt, so
I just want to receive these orders
as soon as invoice arrives.
What I can do here, I can mark these
orders as received on invoice.
I'm going to do it for both.
And now
I will match invoice to these two
orders.
This time I want to use this
get order lines, so I'll pick the first
one.
Line is there and I just
add a second line here
through matched order lines UI.
So
uh
you can see that both orders are here
and this received on invoice flag is
set, meaning that whenever I post this
invoice, receipt will be automatically
posted.
Let's just do something fun
and let's try to
do a partial
invoice and receive.
Now I post the invoice.
Open matched order lines view
and I can see
uh
that receipt are also posted together
with the invoice.
I can go to the order
and see that I got quantity received and
quantity invoiced. All right,
that was
auto posting scenario that you can use
with simple orders. And now let's do
something more complex. Let's try to
use order matching with
item which is tracked and
where we use directed put away and pick
location. Let's use the item that has
item tracking, serial item tracking.
And let's
take a vendor that uses directed put
away and pick location.
So I got those two orders.
Location is white, which is directed put
away and pick.
And then
item is serialized, so we got some
serial numbers.
Same goes for the second order.
Now let's see if we can
match invoice towards that.
And here since we have a directed put
away and pick location, the process is
slightly different.
>> [snorts]
>> I can still use get order lines in the
same way as before, so I just choose the
line. But if I want to add line manually
I will need to
match [snorts] it before I
uh
set up the quantity. So I'm going to add
VMS location and if I try to put
quantity now, I will get an error that
it is not allowed.
So what I need to do, I need to
>> [snorts]
>> match it first.
So I'm going to go and choose both order
lines.
>> [snorts]
>> Yes, and I already posted receipt for
this demo, so you see the whole
structure is here.
And now I can set my quantity without
any errors.
You
also
might notice that we
have [snorts] item tracking entries
action here
meaning that
I can see which
>> [snorts]
>> serial numbers I am uh
invoicing from here.
>> [snorts]
>> And here I also see a new uh field,
receipt shipment number,
showing me uh to which receipt uh these
serial numbers are belong to.
>> [snorts]
>> I can also
see all the
tracking information in a in a in a
normal way.
Yep. So, let me post the invoice.
And done. Mhm.
I'm go here and opening the order.
And you see
order is completely received and
invoiced.
So, to wrap it up, uh with this new
capability, you are able to cover much
more real-world scenarios and you can be
in a better control of your invoicing
and receiving.
Check description for more information
and thank you for watching.